[zombie-like moaning]
[groaning and moaning]
[thumping head]
Any sign
of the illicit invaders?
Not seeing a peep
with my peepers.
[grumbling]
I suppose that doesn't
make a difference,
considering we couldn't even
see the attackers
when they were attacking us
last night.
[scoffing] Invisibility
requires reams of permits
and background checks.
Who could our assailants
have been?
Who knows,
but if they return,
they won't be invisible
to how hard I'm gonna
bludgeon them with fines.
[panicking]
They can't come back.
I can't handle it
if they come back!
What they did to Carl B,
and Debra,
and the entire HR department!
Shh! Don't panic!
Look at them, their minds,
their souls, are gone!
It can't happen to us,
I have so much to live for!
Well, a few things
to live for.
I love my ergonomic chair.
[unearthly note blowing]
The unauthorized visitors
are back!
[blowing unearthly note]
Let's hit that scofflaw
harder than I hit
the fourth floor vending machine
when it doesn't release
my snacks!
[weapon powering up]
[agent yelping,
unearthly note blowing]
[screaming in terror]
[groaning]
[blowing unearthly note]
[♪♪♪]
[ThunderFang]
The Source Dragons
will rue the day
they rejected me.
[cackling wickedly]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[motors revving]
The sun's setting already?
Feels like the days
are getting shorter.
[Arin] Maybe it's
a magical Mysterium thing?
Ras, why are we stopping?
The dwellers of the Underworld
do not appreciate
the presence of the living,
so entrances to their land
don't remain in the same place
for long.
I thought the Spectral Lands
were where people passed through
to whatever's after this life.
So then, what's the Underworld?
[Ras] Similar,
but only disgraced
warriors end up there,
which is irrelevant
to our goals.
All we need is access
to the Forge of the Forgotten.
And this Forge will bring
my parents back?
The Forge will enable us
to create a dragon icon
to summon a Source Dragon,
the first step to--
Reversing the Merge, I know.
I just want to get to the part
where you bring my parents back.
I have our heading.
[engine revving]
Enough, Sora!
[sighing]
You're no fun.
[revving]
You shouldn't make him mad.
I need him.
He needs us, Arin.
He wouldn't be dragging
a couple of kid Ninja
around with him
if he wasn't desperate for help.
Just don't mess this up for me.
[revving motor]
[Ras] We're here.
Uh, you sure about that?
Yes, somewhere here
is the passage
to the underworld.
It's not even being guarded?
Okay, did we just see a mirage?
I don't exactly know
how mirages work.
There has to be some way in.
[heavy footsteps]
[roaring]
This thing doesn't look
happy to see us.
Maybe we're falling
into a stereotype
about scary skeleton monsters.
It could be friendly.
Excuse us!
We're just looking for
a way into the Under--
Whaa--!
[Jay] Ah, what a class!
Who knew I could paint?
I didn't know I could paint.
I told you you could.
You have a lot of skills,
actually,
because you used to be a Ninja.
Ugh, not this again.
Just when I thought
you were kind of fun.
"Kind of"?
Oh, I am a lot of fun.
You've become the fuddy-duddy.
"Fuddy-duddy"?
Did you learn that word
from our dance lessons
with the retirees?
Maybe.
Those lessons
were the bee's knees.
[calling] Lloyd!
Wyldfyre?
You mean Doyll and Filedwire!
Right.
We're home!
Hmm.
They should have been
back by now.
Hopefully they found a lead
on Arin's parents.
Hopefully,
but the Land of Lee
does have a lot of distractions.
Let's look for them,
just to make sure Wyldfyre
isn't eating
the ice cream hotel.
It's no use
trying to escape that cage.
It's designed to optimize
your journey to friendship.
Just like Elway here,
steadily having all the negative
thought-pollution about me
cleaned from his mind.
The things I'll do
for my friends, really.
[Lloyd] I knew you had
to have brainwashed
everyone down here, Lee!
What?
Of course I didn't do that!
Everyone in the Land of Lee
has chosen to be here!
Well, almost everyone.
Once in a long while,
some no-goodnik figures out
the "truths" I sing
about the Merge
are not based in actual fact,
and so those few have to be...
corrected.
[cage buzzing open]
Hello, Elway!
Hope you enjoyed
your meditation!
Just wondering,
what do you think
about your old pal, Lee?
Lee is a loyal, kind,
and completely
non-deceptive friend.
Don't worry,
when my little tentacled buddy
gets rested up,
you two will be next to learn
the magic of friendship.
[shouting in frustration]
Heat is better than green.
[grunting with effort] H'yah!
That doesn't seem right.
What can this cage
be made out of?
Oh, no, not now...
[vision whooshing]
[Strength symbol]
We cannot get involved
with mortal problems.
It only poisons us
and our powers.
Weakens us!
[Motion symbol]
Like it or not,
ThunderFang is a threat
to the Source Dragons.
[Life symbol] Only because
we got involved with mortals
in the first place.
We should never
have made that promise
to the First Spinjitzu Master.
[Strength] I voted against
granting boons to the First,
if you remember.
[Motion] We all recall
it was a split
until the Source Dragon
of Balance favored the mortals
and became the deciding vote,
but Balance
is no longer with us,
and we must reach a consensus
on our own.
The only way
to truly defeat ThunderFang
is through
the Arc Dragon of Focus.
[Focus] No.
I will not aid this time.
[Energy] If it is so voted,
you shall,
like the last time.
[Focus] I also regret
getting involved with mortals.
It has brought us nothing
but pain and danger.
We should remove
our presence entirely.
[Motion]
It's too late for that.
ThunderFang has more power
than you realize.
He will force his way
onto this council
and destroy everything.
[Focus] My answer is still no.
[Motion] You do realize
that a mortal could activate
the Arc Dragon of Focus.
[Strength] Impossible!
[Motion] If both halves
of the dragon
were released from their sleep
and focused upon soul energy...
[Strength sniffing]
Is there a mortal here now?
[gasping]
How could you take a nap
at a time like this?
Some leader.
The Source Dragons...
ThunderFang is back.
[gasping]
Something tells me
they don't want us here, Ras!
[Ras grunting with effort]
[roaring]
Aah!
[Kai] All right, Frak,
you got this.
Remember,
half the battle is up here.
You want me
to head-butt the bamboo?
What? No!
Just hit them normal,
but with mental focus.
Begin!
H'ah! H'yah!
H'yah!
[panting]
How was that?
You're really improving.
[Geo] Refreshments!
Thanks, Geo.
Can you fuse that bamboo
so we can do another run?
You bet.
Tea, two sugars,
two more sugars, and honey,
just the way you like it.
[gasping] How'd you know?
Hey, who made snacks?
-[Geo] I did!
-[gagging]
Sponge Wafers
with a hint of mint.
Personal recipe.
[wheezing] This just sucked
all the moisture out of my body.
[gulping tea]
[Fritz] Kai! Kai!
Check out what we scavenged
from the geyser last week!
[hoarsely] Can't wait.
Cool weapons, right?
[coughing]
The Prismatic Blades?
They went missing
when we fought ThunderFang.
No one knew where they went,
so how'd they wind up
in the Land of Lost--
Oh, yeah, I hear it now.
Frak, this time,
I want you to use
your elemental quake power
to shatter the targets
from below.
[ground rumbling]
[yelping]
It's like
the Earth is screaming!
You can feel it too?
I sense it everywhere
in the Merged Lands,
but it's especially loud here.
What's causing it?
Not sure.
All I know is a while back,
the ghostly voice of Master Wu
called me on a mission.
[Master Wu] Cole...
Huh?
[Cole] After walking
for what seemed like forever,
I found the place
that must be the source
of the screaming Earth.
I could sense something
deep under ground,
something big.
[ground rumbling]
I tried and tried,
but couldn't get the object up.
Why would Wu send me out there
if I couldn't do
anything about it?
Unless he wanted me to do more,
and I just failed him
or something?
Whoa.
What could be down there?
Let's check it out right now!
That sounds like a whole...
ugh, what's the word
for it? "Journey."
I for one am not in the mood
to go walking forever.
I have something
that might help.
[whooshing]
[♪♪♪]
You made this?
Just fused together
a bunch of parts
that wound up
in the Land of Lost Things.
No big deal.
You could give Sora
a run for her money.
Okay, a journey it is.
Yes!
[grunting with impact]
Arin! No!
Yaah!
Sora!
You just did Spinjitzu!
Did I?
I did, right? Right?
[rumbling]
[roaring]
Hup!
[roaring battle cry]
[roaring]
[gasping]
Mortals!
You gained victory
through the only thing
the dishonorable warriors
of the underworld
have ever respected--
strength!
Your passage has been granted.
Bone stairs into darkness...
Cool.
Love hanging out with you guys.
[Ras] Move.
[whistling nonchalantly]
Hey, Lee.
Well, definitely following us.
Who's the paranoid egotist now?
Both things can be true.
Come on.
[beeping]
So this "backstage" area
is supposed to be
a Lee-only zone?
Mm-hmm.
That's what Ellen Q
said at needlepoint class.
She also told me
she sneaks extra cherries
at the ice cream social,
but that sounded like
her problem.
[lock beeping open]
Got it.
Pretty good for someone
who claims to have
never been a ninja.
Maybe I was just a good thief.
Wish I had one of these.
[kicking]
In fact,
I deserve a little treat.
What did you just do?
You'll find out.
[chiseling]
Carving gravestones?
Read the names.
Strong McCoolguy.
Nya McCoolguy.
Dyoll Donmagar.
Filedwire Donmagar!
They're making
gravestones for us?
[chuckling]
Time to roll the bones!
You got a spare-- rib!
[laughing]
[Ras] You two!
Direct me to
the Forge of the Forgotten!
Sure.
Second left past the--
You dummy,
why you tellin'
some random mortal
where the Forge is?
Ah! He asked all forceful.
You know I respond
to strong leadership.
You bonehead!
Look, mortal,
we'll only tell you
if you can beat us
at a bone-rolling challenge.
Winner gets--
Okay, you win.
Ah! Second left
past the demon tree.
Third passage.
You can't miss it!
Sorry about him.
He can get a little intense.
Here you go.
Yeah, we know the deal.
We've worked with
people like that.
Guess that's it.
How do we work it?
[gasping]
It's not responding
to my powers.
Must be magic,
'cause it's not tech.
[Ras] It is far
beyond technology.
[pulling lever]
[deep rumbling and hissing]
It's big enough to crawl into.
The Forge is powered
when someone enters
the Casket of Bones.
Creepy.
How do they get back out?
They don't.
Huh?
Why do you think I tolerated
your presence for so long?
I thought you needed my help.
That's true,
in a way.
No.
I won't let you do this.
Rather it was you, Arin?
No one dies here today, Ras!
Using this Forge
is the only way
to save your parents.
Someone is going
into that casket.
You...
or her?
Have I ever steered you wrong?
You were a weakling
when I found you,
and I turned you into a warrior.
Warriors must make
difficult choices,
especially if they truly love
their parents.
[quietly] Be stealthy.
[headstones tumbling heavily]
Uh...
[quietly] Stealthy starting now!
Pretty surreal to be looking
at your own grave marker.
Does this mean
Lee's planning to kill us?
It doesn't make any sense.
[gasping] Look!
Arin's parents?
They really are dead.
You were wrong, Jay.
Look here.
Melba.
We met her yesterday
at dance class.
She's old, but definitely
not in that grave.
I've got a hunch.
It's empty!
I bet all these graves
are empty!
But why?
What if Lee puts these here
to stop anyone who comes looking
for lost loved ones?
They'd think the person
they're looking for is dead
and give up.
That way, no one would ever find
his hidden
underground community.
[Lee] Hey!
Who's lightninging
my cemetery?
Count and Countess McCoolguy?
Stop!
[Arin] This wasn't
part of the deal, Ras.
I never told you
our mission would be easy.
You have never been closer
to bringing your parents back.
Show me you have the courage
to do what needs to be done.
It's not fair.
Have the strength
to save your family.
Sora is my family too.
You are defying me?
I should have never trusted you
in the first place.
So be it.
[roaring]
[Arin screaming]
[Ras grunting]
[roaring in rage]
H'ah!
[both screaming]
[Arin and Sora screaming]
[groaning]
[roaring]
You will enter that casket.
You can't win, Ras,
'cause we have
one thing you don't.
[Arin] Each other!
[grunting with effort]
Your loyalty to each other
will be your downfall!
[slamming, rock crumbling]
[crying out]
[grunting with effort]
[heavy slamming]
[impact echoing]
[grunting with effort]
Let's go
before he digs himself out.
[exhaling deeply]
Nothing beats the fresh air
of the living world.
They're gone.
They're gone forever.
[sobbing gasp]
[sobbing quietly]
You once told me
change can be scary.
I'm scared, Sora.
[♪♪♪]
Now that Lee's onto us,
we need to find
Lloyd and Wyldfyre, and--
I'm guessing Lee can still live
even with a few less
of his bodies.
Let's find out.
Jay, we can't kill him.
It's not the Ninja way.
I'm not a Ninja!
H'yah!
[woman gasping]
That was Spinjitzu.
You're the Ninja!
Our son, Arin,
was your biggest fan.
[gasping]
[♪♪♪]